Guide to the Jean-Pierre Habicht papers, 1940-2007
Habicht, Jean-Pierre papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jean-Pierre Habicht papers, 1940-2007
29-2-3679
Jean-Pierre. Habicht
10 cubic feet
Correspondence, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, publications, reviews and subject files concerning Habicht's international work in nutrition and epidemiology and with the World Health Organization.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor in the Division of Nutritional Sciences, Cornell University.
Jean-Pierre Habicht obtained medical training in Switzerland, further pediatric training in the United States, a Ph.D. in nutritional biochemistry from MIT and public health training from Harvard, worked in Guatemala for the Institute of Nutrition of Central America as a World Health Organization medical officer in charge of primary health care and epidemiological studies, and then worked for the United States National Center for Health Statistics on nutritional surveillance. He came to Cornell University in 1977 to develop a program of research and study in nutritional epidemiology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, publications, reviews and subject files concerning Habicht's international work in nutrition and epidemiology and with the World Health Organization.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Habicht, Jean-Pierre.; Habicht, Jean-Pierre.; Cornell University--Faculty.; World Health Organization.
Subjects:
Nutrition--Developing nations.; Epidemiology.; Nutrition.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Box 10
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 1-3, 10
Series III. Program Reviews
Box 3
Series IV. Grants
Box 3
Series V. Publications
Boxes 4-7
Subseries V.a. Abstracts
Subseries V.b. Reports, Newsletters, Working Papers
Subseries V.c. Journals
Subseries V.d. Books
Subseries V.e. Unpublished Manuscripts
Subseries V.f. In Progress Manuscripts
Series VI. Reports and Studies
Box 7
Series VII. International WHO Work
Boxes 8, 9
Series VIII. Reviews by Jean-Pierre
Box 10
Series IX. Center for Research and development in Nutrition (CRDN) Reports
Box 10
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Biography Pages (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Awards (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jean-Pierre Habicht'sJob Offers, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jean-Pierre Habicht's Naturalization Status, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1974, 1979, 1884, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Jean-Pierre Habicht- Cornell job offer, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jean-Pierre Habicht- WHO personal history, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Active grants, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Photo of Jean-Pierre Habicht, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Who's Who in Frontier Science and Technology; Who's Who Among Human Services Professionals, 1983;1992 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Who's Who in Science and Engineering; American Men and Women of Science, 1991-1995;1982,2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Who's Who in Education; Who's Who in Medicine, 1992-2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Who's Who in America, 1996-2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Who's Who in the World, 1998-2003 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Articles of Habicht, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1999,2002 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Symposium celebrating Habicht's career-program, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 1A)
  - Calendar created as party souvenir with photos by Jean-Pierre and Gretel Pelto, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 16-B)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence A, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence B, 1984-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bassett Hospital in Cooperstown, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Ken, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Besharov, Douglas, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Blum, Lauren, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence C, 1997-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Catholic Relief Services, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CFNCPP, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chyba, Christopher, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curricula Review, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Committee on International Nutrition, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - China Projects, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence D, 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence D, 1986-2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Demography, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Devaney, Barbara, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - DNS Committees, 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - DNS Curriculum Committee, 1987-1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - DNS Department Issues, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - DNS Institutional Development- CSRS Review, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - DNS Nutrition Intervention and Policy Committee, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - DNS Nutrition and Policy Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - DNS Nutrition and Policy Committee, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - DNS Nutrition and Policy Committee Search Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - DNS Planning Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - DNS Senior Research Associates- Ad Hoc Committee, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - DNS Small Grants Committee, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - DNS Strategic Planning Committee, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence E, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence F, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Field of International Development, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence G, 1985-1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence G, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gray, Elizabeth, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Growth Monitoring, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence H, 1986-2002 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Harvard, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - International Journal of Epidemiology, 1988-2002 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - International Society for Research on Human Milk and Lactation, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - IFPRI-Advisory Committee-Honduras, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Johns Hopkins, 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence L, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence K, 1986-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence L, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence M, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mardones Restat, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mardones Restat, 1983- Jun 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Memories, prior to 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Merchant, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Morley, David, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mutamba, Judith, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence N, 1980-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Nesheim, Mal, 1978-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Nesheim, Mal, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence O, 1978-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence P, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence P, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pew Program, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pisacane, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Public Policy Graduate Field, Public Affairs Program, 1995, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence R, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence R, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Rush, David, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Research Proposals Review, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence S, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence S, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence S, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Segovia, Carmen, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Shrimpton, Roger, 1989-2001 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sigman, Marian, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Society for International Nutrition Research, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Stann, Jeff, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence T, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Task Force for Nominating DNS Director, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1989-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Thrasher Research Fund, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Thrasher Research Fund- Financial Records, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence U, 1988-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - United Nations University, 1989-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence V, 1985-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Visiting Fellows, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Visiting Fellows, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence W, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - World Health Organization, 1996-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - World Health Organization, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - World Health Organization, 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence X, 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Y, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Y, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Z, 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Memos, Reports, Publications, 1974-1981 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Memos, Reports, Publications, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Memos, Reports, Publications- Concerning maternal and infant nutrition in developing countries, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Memos, Reports, Publications, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1981-2000 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence to and from Bert Garza, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Memos Concerning the DNS Director's Search, 1997-20003 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Series III. Program Reviews
  - Program Reviews, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Program Reviews, 1996-2002 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series IV. Grants
  - Grants, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Grants, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Grants, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Series V. Publications
  - Abstracts
    - Index choronological order (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Abstracts, 1971-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Abtracts, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Abtracts, 1993-2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Abtracts, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Newsletters, Working Papers
    - Index, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1971-1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Publications, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Publications, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Publications, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Publications, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1994-1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Publications, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Publications, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Journals
    - Index (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Journals, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Journals, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Journals, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Journals, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Journals, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Journals, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Journals, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Journals, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Journals, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Journals, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Journals, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Journals, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Journals, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Journals, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Journals, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Journals, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Journals, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Books
    - Index (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Books, 1961-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Books, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Books, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Books, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Books, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Books, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Books, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Books, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Books, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Books, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Books, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Books, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Books, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Books, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Books, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Books, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Books, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts
    - Index (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - In Progress Manuscripts
    - Index (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - A-C, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - D-F, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - F-H, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - H-L, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - M-R, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - R-S, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - S-W, Various Dates (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Series VI. Reports and Studies
  - Cornell Nutritional Surveillance Program- "Nutrional Surveillance", Aug 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Nutritional Surveillance Program- "Principles for Evaluation of On-going Programs", May 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Nutritional Surveillance Program- "An Outline Program for Developing a Nutritional Surveillance System in NYS", May 1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Tunisian Fortification Study-Correspondence, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Measuring the Coverage, Effectiveness and Efficiency of Health Care (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Measuring the Coverage, Effectiveness and Efficiency of Health Care (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Medical Evaluation of the Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants and Children" (WIC) Voume II, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - WIC Resources, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - WHO Articles on Benefits of Breastfeeding, 1986-2003 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - WHO Articles on Benefits of Breastfeeding, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - WHO- Expert Consultation on Optimal Duration of Exclusive Breastfeeding, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Summary of Data Sets to be used in Describing the Nutritional Condition of NYS Residents", January 1990 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - INCAP Publications to 1973 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - International Food Policy Research Institute, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Series VII. International WHO Work
  - Explanatory Text Concerning the Work of the Primary Health Care Working Group Set up by HPC (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Standards for Skeletal Age- by J.M. Tanner and R.H. Whitehouse, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Telling a Biographical Age of the Preschool Child from Hand-Wrist Radiographs", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Manual of Anthropometric Studies for Latin America and the Caribbean- Pan American Health Organization, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Estudio Comparativo de Los Sistemas de Adiestramiento y Utilizacion de Promotones de salud en Guatemala" Indira de Beausset, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Socioeconomic and Biomedical Anlaysis of Nutrition Birth Interval and Infant Development" Rand Corp., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama- The Effect of Birth Weight of Timing of Supplementation During Pregnancy, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro American y Panama- Various Studies, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro American y Panama-Coding (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Anthropometric Field Methods. Criteria for Selection- Habicht, Yarbrough, Martorell; Materials on WHO Conference on outcome measurement in the assessment of intervention programs in developing countries, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - U.S.-Japan Malnutrition Panel-Meeting Minutes, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Public Health Association- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - International Health Society- Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "The Relationship between Physical Growth and Infant Behavioral Development in Rural Guatemala", August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "The Effects of food Supplementation on the Cognitive Development of Rural Guatemalan Children" INCAP, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "The INCAP Longitudinal Study of Malnutrition and Mental Development" INCAP, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "The Determinants of Infant Behavioral Development in Rural Guatemala", April 1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "The Determinants of Infant Behavioral Development in Rural Guatemala", April 1978 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "An Integrated Social Science Program at the Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama (INCAP)", May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "The Effects of Food Supplementation on Cognitive Development Among Rural Guatemalan Children", May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "Effects of Protein-Calorie Dietary Interventions on Human Growth, Morbidity and Mortality"- proposal submitted to the Agency for International Developmet from INCAP- I, May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "Effects of Protein-Calorie Dietary Interventions on Human Growth, Morbidity and Mortality"- proposal submitted to the Agency for International Developmet from INCAP- II, May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Was there an Increment in Total Nutrient Intake?", May 1978 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "The Dietary Impact of Food Supplementation in the Guatemalan Longitudinal Study of Malnutrition and Mental Development"- INCAP, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - "Differential Effects of Food Supplementation on Body Size and Maturity"- INCAP, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "Measuring Mental Development in Rural Guatemala"- INCALA, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Food Supplementation and Growth from Birth to Seven Years of Age"- INCAP, August 1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Guidelines for Review of US Nutrition Surveillance Systems, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Food and Drug Administration-Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - WHO-Correspondence and memos, 1978-1983 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - "Malnutrition and Mental Development: the INCAP Longitudinal Field Study", May 1979 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - US-Japan Malnutrition Panels- Proceedings- "Methodologies for Human Population Studies in Nutrition Related to Health", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Proposal for a Program of Research, Training, and Information Dissemination- "The Family in Economic Development: Promoting Growth through People", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - International Vitamin A Consultative Group (IVACG) - The Nutrition Foundation, 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Grant- Statistical Methods for Population Supplemental Trials, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Grant-Statistical Methods for Population Supplemental Trials, 1979-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - WHO-Birthweight Report, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - International Nutrition Program-Annual Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - International Nutrition Program, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Haiti-Consultant in Nutrition, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Uses of Birth Weight Data in Public Health Planning and Practice- WHO Working Group, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - WHO/PAHO Regional Program on Action-Oriented Research in Nutrition Through Primary Health Care Services, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - WHO Nutrition Program, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Allatiement Maternel En Situation Nutritionnelle Critique:Adaptations Et Limites", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology- Scientific Working Group, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - UNICEF, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - USDA-Fellowships, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - WHO-Review Nutrition Proposals, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Workshop-Demographic and Health Surveys, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - International Food Policy Research Institute Food Consumption and Nutrition Policy Research Program: An Overview of Research Activities, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) Final Report, July 1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence from Switzerland, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - International Vitamin A Consultative Group (IVACG) Revision of Chapter III-"Evaluation of Selected Vitamin A Intervention Strategies", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Symposium-Thelastic Infertility- paper, slide, presentation, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - International Symposium on Food, Nutrition and Social Economic Development- Beijing, China, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - International Symposium on Food, Nutrition and Social Economic Development- Beijing, China, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Seminar Report- "Child Health Priorities for the 1990s", 1991 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Institute of Medicine- Committee on Scientific Evaluation WIC Nutrition Risk Criteria- Meeting, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - "Lessons Learned and New Directions in Community- Based Nutrition Monitoring" DNS Workshop, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Committee on International Nutrition- Vitamin C in Food Aid Commodities- Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Processed Complementary Foods in Latin American: Why, Where and How?- Consultation- PAHO/WHO, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Conference-Honduras, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - WHO- Dept. of Child and Adolescent Helath and Development- Technical Steering Committee, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Strengthening, Monitoring and Evaluation in the World Banks Nutrition Portfolio- World Bank Meeting, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - United Nations University Report to the World Bank: Review of the Evidence for a Moratorium on the Activities of the Bangladesh Integrated Nutrition Program, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Assessing the Influence of Frontline Worker Skills Characteristics and Work Context on the Effectiveness of Behavorial Change Communication in Haiti-Proposal Submitted to the International Food Policy Research Institute, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Series VIII. Reviews by Jean-Pierre
  - American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 1983-2003 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - American Journal of Epidemiology, 1980-2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - American Journal of Public Health, 1979-2003 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Various Journals, 1998-2003 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - France Begins Work, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Series IX. Center for Research and development in Nutrition (CRDN) Reports
  - Indonesia, December 1978 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Indonesia, May 1979 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Indonesia, January 1980 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Indonesia, November-December 1980 (Box 10, Folder 34)